# 丰收棒子鱼 金玉满堂
Corn fish
(aka. Gold & Jade)
# 过年了过年了 兄弟们过年好
Happy new year!
# 你看这老礼 过年了
That's the traditional gesture for the new year
# 刚子 今天做什么菜啊
(Gang, what are you cooking today?)
# 今天咱做一个丰收棒子鱼
I'm cooking the corn fish today
# 也叫金玉满堂
aka. Gold & Jade
# 这名起的好啊
What a nice name
# 师父在旁边呢
Your master is right next to you
# 有谱了
Everything's under control.
# 好
Alright
# 这是什么鱼
What kind of fish is it?
# 草鱼
Cao Yu(Grass carp)
# 北方叫草鱼 南方叫皖鱼
Known as Cao Yu in Northern China
Wan Yu in the South.
# 欢子看你刀工了啊
It's all up to your knife skills today.
# 看看我们的师弟啊
Look at all him.
# 这也太专业了
How professional!
# 看啊 鱼刺都剔完了
Look, all the bones are removed.
# 该改刀了啊
Time to shape it with my knife.
# 欢子今天你的刀功 可就要考验你了
Huan, we are putting your knife skills to a test today
# 直来直下
Slice it vertically
# 因为要体现出它的玉米粒来 形状
It has to resemble the shape of a corn seed
# 不能断啊
Don't cut through
# 把皮刺破了就麻烦了
You should not slice through the skin.
# 烧油
Oil in to the wok.
# 前两年我参加厨王争霸时候做过这道菜
I used to cook this dish when I was in a competition.
# 也没有拿到奖吧
Did you win though?
# 拿奖了 拿了啊
I did, I did!
# 揭底了
The hidden history!
# 没拿奖师傅肯定没在
You didn't win because your master was not there helping you.
# 你看我净说实话了
That's so true!
# 这小魏参加厨王争霸打了几次擂
He actually participated in the competition several times.
# 而且还全部都赢了
And he won!
# 后来你知道吗 就上国外去打擂了
Later, you know, he went abroad to compete
# 所有的五星级酒店的大厨全输了
So many master chefs from 5-star hotels did't make it in the competition.
# 就小魏一人打平了
He was the only one to end up with a draw.
# 这小魏为什么打平了呀
Why is that?
# 小魏临时变阵 我做西餐了 跟你们一样
He changed his strategy to cooking western dishes. Just like other chefs.
# 这老外没法评了
It was too difficult to judge. So it was a draw.
# 得的分都一样 打一个平手
50-50
# 所以说你看到没有啊
So, did you realize?
# 今年这不是鼠年嘛
It's the year of the rat this year
# 鼠年就贼啊 风格有点像二伯
Rats are smart
(Just like Er Bai)
# 贼啊 临时变了
He was smart to change his strategy.
# 刀功得粗细一致啊
You have to slice it evenly.
# 你不能说光粗细一致
Not only the thickness has to be even
# 关键是什么呀 他不能把这皮给剌断了是不是
What' important is that the skin has to stay intact.
# 得深到什么时候啊 贴到皮
Slice as close as touching the skin.
# 但皮还不能剌 就达到目的了 是不是
Without breaking the skin. That's the point.
# 小魏为什么选择 全是直刀法啊
Why do you only cut it vertically?
# 直刀第一个 它出来就跟玉米的形状是一样的
Firstly to make it look like corn seeds.
# 第二这操作比较便捷
Secondly, it was easier.
# 最关键是什么呀
What's the most important?
# 最关键是
The most important is...
# 你得说对了
(No pressure)
# 最关键的最关键是什么 你知道吗
Do you know what's most important?
# 跟大爷不是一门派
We have a different style than Da Ye.
# 大爷是唰唰唰 坡着
Da Ye does it at an angle
# 咱就得玩直的
We slice it vertically.
# 他玩直的咱就得玩斜的
If he goes vertical, then we will take an angle.
# 所以说千万别跟他一样
You have to be different from Da Ye
# 小魏啊 你千万别上你大爷的当
Don't listen to Da Ye
# 今年是鼠年了啊 用的全是计谋啊你知道吗
We have to be smart in the year of Rat.
# 大爷和我师父都是大智慧
Both of you are smart!
# 你的师父不是你的亲师父
(He's not your real master)
# 胜似我的亲师父
then he is better than my real master.
# 你又上了他的道了吧
You see, he tricked you again.
# 你是磕头的徒弟
You became my student after with an officially ceremony.
# 怎么不是亲师父呢
How come that I'm not your real master?
# 你就上了他的道了
He tricked you again.
# 还是师父转得快
I wasn't smart enough for that.
# 我是你的亲大爷啊
Yet I am your real Da Ye (Grandmaster)
# 你大爷还是你大爷
The grandmaster is always the grandmaster
# 老玉米出来了啊 出来了啊
There comes the corn shape
# 一个大玉米一个小玉米
A big one and a small one
# 这就起来了啊
Here we go
# 年年有余
Fish for fortune!
# 金玉满堂
Gold and Jade everywhere!
# 丰收棒子鱼
The corn fish!
# 先腌味
First, marination .
# 料酒 对 盐
Rice wine, and salt
# 胡椒粉来点
A bit of pepper
# 千万得少
Not to much
# 老饭骨的黄酒来一点 太多了上色
Our own rice wine. （just a little bit, you don't want the color in it）
# 香香的 香香的
Smells good!
# 多了
(Too much?) It's OK.
# 不多不多
It's not too much
# 棒子鱼是个老菜
This is a traditional dish
# 是个传承的菜
Passed down for generations.
# 但是你看我们祖孙三代
But between us three generations
# 带有传承的意义 为什么啊
There's a special meaning in the traditional dish.
# 你看这个菜啊 手法上是个老菜 但是又是个新菜
Skill wise, it is an old dish. But there is something new
# 新菜新在哪儿呢
New in what?
# 你看到没有 这是打好的汁
Check the sauce out
# 里面有榴莲有芒果
There's Durian and Mango in it
# 所以说这个汁非常好
Now that's special
# 这个就是一个新的口味出现了 在北京诞生了
It's a new flavor for this dish in Beijing.
# 什么鱼 榴芒鱼
So it is "Durian-Mango fish".
# 不能叫榴芒鱼
That's a bad name!
# 小魏给起一个名字
Think of a better name.
# 榴莲芒果棒棒鱼 榴莲芒果棒棒鱼
Durian-Mango-Corn fish.
# 这有点绕嘴了
it's almost a tongue twister!
# 这火真旺啊
That's high heat
# 小魏 这就行
That's ready
# 你看这淀粉挂得多好
That's how you coat it with starch
# 这个挂淀粉叫什么手法
What's that technique?
# 这个是先上浆等于先给它入味 入完味以后给它拍淀粉 这叫拍淀粉
The idea is to first marinate it before coating it with starch.
# 脱浆 拍粉
Dry it, then coat it.
# 咱这个没有脱浆 这没有脱浆 直接就拍粉了 腌好之后就直接拍粉了
We didn't dry it, we coat it directly with starch
# 这没脱浆
Straight out of marination.
# 这属于焦溜做鱼的方法
It's a special technique called "Jiao Liu"
# 焦溜还得挂糊呢 还得挂湿糊
But "Jiao Liu" needs a wet batter
# 下锅了
Here we go.
# 咱油温得七成
Oil temperature at around 200~240°C
# 六七成就行
Something like 180~240°C
# 这个老玉米棒子
That's like an old corn!
# 正好这也是咱们春节了 做这一个菜
It fits perfectly in the Chinese new year
# 颜色金黄
It has a golden color.
# 老玉米又代表着丰收 五谷丰登
The corn represents a good harvest.
# 糖醋口 外焦里嫩
It has a sweet-sour flavor. Crispy on the outside but tender inside.
# 又加入了芒果和榴莲
With Mango and Durian.
# 原名叫葡萄鱼 葡萄鱼
It used to be named "Grape fish"
# 关键在家里炸 要注意安全 这很重要
Be extra careful if you cook it at home.
# 油量比较大
It needs to be deep-fried.
# 跟大爷炸的油条一样
It's almost like frying dough by Da Ye
# 我就吃大爷油条
I like the deep-fried dough made by Da Ye
# 调味是关键啊
Seasoning is the key!
# 这一步是什么啊
What's this step? Making the sauce?
# 师兄 该做汁了
Let's prepare the sauce
# 我们先把汁浇上
Some water
# 先加点水 加水后 给它打这个玉米汁
Plain water in, to make the sauce.
# 这是先熬糖汁吧
So first we will make a sweet base? Right!
# 要想甜 必加盐
You need salt to bring out the sweetness
# 我师父教我定味的
I learnt it from my master
# 行了 盐够了
OK that's enough salt.
# 有淀粉吗 有淀粉
Do you need starch? Yes!
# 加汁吧 挂糖汁 柠檬榴莲芒果汁 挂好了 柠檬榴莲芒果汁
OK now the sauce. The Lemon-Durian-Mango sauce is in.
# 这个是提勾兑对好的
You need to prepare this beforehand.
# 好 打芡
OK now we add starch.
# 用的什么淀粉 生粉
What starch are you using? Corn or potato starch.
# 这个里面用生粉啊 网友们
Everyone, remember to use corn or potato starch
# 生粉 生粉
Starch in
# 把火关了
Turn off the heat
# 冒泡了
There are bubbles.
# 老饭骨的家宴
Family dinner of Lao Fan Gu.
# 这样它就更细了 看到没有全是淀粉 这样你能让它更加细
See? The sieve gets rid of the lumps and makes the sauce really fine.
# 来点明油
A little bit of oil.
# 油凉
The oil is cold
# 鱼盘 鱼盘来了
The fish please! Here it is!
# 这汁亮堂啊
The sauce is very bright!
# 这师爷和师父指挥的吗
I learnt from the best!
# 师爷指挥的好 这汁够亮啊
Good guidance indeed, lovely sauce!
# 这谁码的坑 啊 这坑下的多大啊
Who came up with the whole "guidance" thing?
# 这坑埋的够大的啊
That's a long story.
# 色泽金黄啊
Lovely golden color.
# 把它浇均匀了
Pour evenly
# 榴芒汁真黄啊
The fruit sauce has a lovely yellow color
# 好 漂亮啊 这镜头感漂亮
Beautiful! Looks great through the lenses.
# 你师爷一指导就是不一样啊
The guidance of Da Ye really helps!
# 色泽金黄 外焦里嫩 色泽金黄 外焦里嫩
Golden brown color, crispy on the outside and tender on the inside.
# 糖醋口 鼓掌
Sweet and sour flavor. Applause!
# 在师爷的指导下用了30分钟 好
With the guidance of Da Ye, we finished in 30 mins.
# 完成了任务
Mission accomplished!
# 这还有个玉米穗
There's the ear of the corn
# 点睛之笔
The final touch.
# 大家看看啊 这就是一个油菜
It's actually just cole.
# 吃完糖醋口了 来一个小油菜清清口
Cole can help clean up your mouth after tasting the sweet and sour sauce.
# 感谢师父
Thanks master.
# 感谢小亮
Thanks Xiao Liang
# 感谢诸位师兄弟
Thanks, everyone!
# 这个丰收棒子鱼 也叫金玉满堂
So here it is, the corn fish, aka, Gold and Jade.
# 在春节的时候啊 玉米也代表着五谷丰登
The corn is a god wish for harvest during the Chinese new year.
# 糖醋口 年年有余的寓意也有了
Sweet and sour flavor, wishes for a lot of fortune and wealth.
# 色彩金黄 口味糖醋
Golden color, sweet and sour.
# 甜甜美美
Sweet and beautiful.
# 增加了榴莲和芒果汁的香气
With added fragrance from Durian and Mango
# 这菜有创新 有传承
A traditional dish with innovation.
# 感谢我师父 感谢我们大家
Special thanks to my master, and everyone.
# 感谢大家
Thank you !
# 开吃
Let's dig in!
# 抄家伙
Let's go!
# 先尝尝玉米粒
Let's try the "seeds" first.
# 香不香 真香
It smells really good.
# 酸不酸 真酸
Sour enough? Yes it's sour enough.
# 这么好的菜 您得说说
You have to comment on this nice dish.
# 金玉满堂 象征着我们国家的兴旺
So, the dish is called Gold and Jade, it wishes for a beautiful future of our country.
# 民族的振兴
The prosper of our nation
# 家族的和谐
The harmony of the families.
# 人民的富裕
The wealth of our people
# 甜甜美美
# 有酸甜苦辣咸
It has all flavors in our lives: sour, sweet, bitter, spicy, salty.
# 人生五味
The five flavors of life.
# 光说好了
What a speech!
# 那喝点什么
Shall we drink something?
# 酒 这摆着酒呢
There's our liquor.
# 喝不喝啊 喝 好酒配好菜 倒上
Good liquor to match the good dish.
# 再来点
Some more
# 来来来 我们一起来
OK let's toast together.
# 全家福啊 我们一起来
Let's toast with the whole family.
# 我们的粉丝在春节来临之际
Best wishes of the new year to our followers
# 做什么菜 吃什么菜
what should you eat for the new year?
# 吃棒子 吃老玉米
The "corn"
# 金玉满堂 健康啊
Gold and Jade!
# 健康啊 粗纤维啊
To health!
# 家人们都辛苦了
Good job everyone.
# 给师父和二伯拜个年
Happy new year to the masters.
# 过年了
Happy new year
# 我是大爷
I am Da Ye
# 我是二伯
I am Er Bai
# 我是三叔
I am San Shu
# 我们是老饭骨
We are Lao Fan Gu
# 欢迎大家订阅 我们老饭骨youtube频道
Please subscribe to our YouTube Channel
# 我们老饭骨组合 就是教大家做菜
We are here to teach you how to cook.
# 传授一些精湛的小厨艺
And to share with you some little tips. Hope you like them.
# 希望大家喜欢 希望全球的美食爱好者喜欢我们
We that hope everyone around the world likes our videos.
# 订阅我们的频道 点亮我们的小铃铛
Subscribe to our channel, and click the reminder bell.
# 同时在这里我们祝全球的华人
Here, we wish everyone
# 万事如意 恭喜发财
A lot of happiness and fortune in the coming new year!